BEN HICKSON SOFTWARE

- **■** bzhickson@gmail.com
- line benhickson.com

ENGINEER

- 423-715-6852
- ♥ Brooklyn, NY
- in benhickson
- O benhickson

Full-stack web developer, experienced with React, Angular, and Rails, and fluent in JavaScript, Ruby, and PHP. Excellent at independent and collaborative work with distributed teams.

Background in the media industry, focused on technical mastery, project management, and client relations, with a track record of delivering work ontime, to-spec, and in-budget. Interested in leveraging machine learning in projects that can benefit society in profound ways.

Skills

FRAMEWORKS

Angular

React

Ruby on Rails

Flask

Express

LANGUAGES

JavaScript

PHP

TypeScript

Ruby

Python

SQL

SKILLS

Application Architecture and Design

Open-source (OSS)

Cloud Deployment

Project Planning and Management

MEDIA

Video Editing

2D Animation

Color Grading

Sound Mixing

File Compression and Delivery Optimization

Experience

Our Hometown Software Engineer

Remote | Brooklyn, NY August 2020 - Current

- Developed and deployed a complete system to orchestrate the error logs and performance analytics of a network of 200+ production websites into a centralized dashboard.
- Currently: Developing a new theme to deploy across the network of sites.

Lonelyleap Film Director of Photography and Post-production Manager

Brooklyn, NY 2013 - 2020

- Led the camerawork and visual style on a wide variety of projects in all corners of the globe.
- Managed the post-production department (resources and staff), supervised output, and optimized storage processes.
- Worked directly with clients and led production teams on many projects, with budgets ranging from \$50k \$300k, for a wide variety of clients, including Google, Nokia, and Uber.
- Collaborated with industry pros and governments around the world, ensuring safety and compliance at all stages.
- Created and managed budget, schedule, and process throughout, ensuring all creative and business goals are achieved, managing a project end-to-end, from first client contact through to final delivery.

Projects

Go Room

App Backend (Rails) | Poker Backend (NodeJS) | Frontend (Angular) | Portfolio Page | Live Site

Browser-based group video chat app (nothing to install!), with extensibility at its core. Perfect for social distancing!

- Implemented as an Angular (version 9) application, with components built for efficient memory management.
- Implemented main backend as a Rails API with a MySQL database, handling authentication with JWT.
- Built a complete multiplayer poker application, leveraging websockets (socket.io), on a NodeJS / Express backend.
- Multi-backend authentication is handled using federated JWTs.
- Implemented a paradigm of authenticated anonymous users, to increase conversions.

Stock Archive

GitHub | Portfolio Page | Live Site (login credentials available upon request)

Content management system for video teams, surfacing unused footage with team members around the world.

- Envisioned, created, and deployed the application in my company, building it into our processes.
- Implemented automation queues to transcode uploaded assets into multiple resolutions and thumbnails.
- Implemented a custom media server to access transcoded assets with a consistent API.
- Built custom tagging and search engine functionality.
- Ensured full security for uploaded assets, and all access is logged for regulatory compliance.
- Integrated Clarifai's AI-powered image recognition technology.

The Bad Idea Machine

Backend (Rails) | Frontend (React) | Portfolio Page | Live Site

Idea Generation Application for Advertising Creatives

- Trained a GPT-2-based neural network to generate ideas in the form of a short "pitch".
- React frontend, Rails backend, JWT Authentication
- Deployed with Netlify and Heroku

Traversalist

GitHub | Portfolio Page | Live Site

A website featuring articles across different themes, at the intersection of science, philosophy, and society.

- Implemented custom routing functionality, optimizing requests for speed.
- Developed a custom image generation and caching engine with the PHP Imagick module, to optimize images.
- Developed a consistent, easy-to-use API for interacting with the image engine and requesting resources.

Education

Flatiron School

2020 - 2020

Full Stack Web Development Immersive, Ruby on Rails and React

Middle Tennessee State University BBA, Finance

2007 - 2011